اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۞
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۞
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا
The time preceding the Prophethood, of Muhammadﷺ was a time of darkness.
However, there were some glimpses of light here and there,
but they were too few and far, in between.
And humanity was in dire need of Hidayah(هداية), guidance.
But again, there were some individuals here and there, scattered apart, who had the sense of right and wrong,
and their hearts directed them to the truth.
And we'll talk about a few of these examples.
One of them is; Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل).
Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل) went out in search of truth,
he traveled out of Makkah searching for the truth, he was from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
but he traveled around in search of guidance.
So, he went to the Jews, and inquired about their religion, but he decided not to follow it.
And then he went to the Christians and inquired about their religion, and decided not to follow it.
And then in the end, he came to learn about the way of Ibrahim عليه السّلام; Al-Hanifiya(الحنفيه), worshipping Allah alone.
And he became a Haneefi(حنيفي); a follower of Ibrahim عليه السّلام.
Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل) was a lone voice in the sea of darkness in Makkah.
Asmaa Bint Abi Bakr(اسماء بنت ابي بكر); she said that I have seen Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل) with his back leaning on Al-Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه).
And he's speaking to his people, of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) and telling them: O people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
none of you is following the way of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم) except myself.
Because the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) use to claim that they are the inheritors of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم),
they are the ones following his path.
But Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل) would tell them none of you is following the true path of Ibrahim عليه السّلام, other than me.
Asmaa(اسماء), the daughter of Abu Bakr(ابو بكر) said:
I saw Zaid Bin Amr Bin Nufail(زيد بن عمرو بن نفيل), leaning his back against the Ka'aba(اَلْكَعْبَه) saying;
O tribe of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) by Him in Whose hand is Zaid(زيد) soul,
not one of you apart from myself follows the religion of Ibrahim(اِبْراهِيْم).
He would also say O God if only I knew the way most favored by you, I would worship you by it,
But I don't know.
Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), he believes in Allah, he knows the truth,
but he doesn't know how to apply it how to worship Allah سبحانه وتعالى,
he doesn't have Shariah(شريعه) to follow.
He has the belief, he has the faith and he wants to pray to Allah سبحانه وتعالى, but he doesn't know, how?
And there are people like Zaid(زيد) in every time
people whose hearts guide them to the truth, they know that there's no god but one,
and they want to worship Allahسبحانه وتعالى
but they haven't been exposed to the way to do it.
And in fact, some reverts have been through such an experience.
I know, of one brother who later on became a Muslim, he became Muslim at the age of 40.
He used to say that in my heart, I knew that Allah is one and Allah had no son,
and I would not drink and I would not eat pork because I thought that these are not good.
And I would avoid the sins that people would participate in I felt that in my heart
and I wanted to pray to Allah سبحانه وتعالى, but I would not know how?
Until I learned about Islam(The Religion Of Ibrahim عليه السّلام).
So, here you have Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل) going though the same experience,
he is saying O Allah I want to pray to you, but I don't know how.
And we'll talk about Abu Dharr(ابو ذر), who has some similar words.
It's amazing to see Ya'ani(يعني) how many things Zaid(زيد) knew by his natural disposition.
For example, He would not participate in the killing of girls that existed in Makkah.
In fact whenever he hears about father about to kill his daughter,
he would go to that father and say Give her to me, I'll take care of her!
So, he would adopt all of these girls and raise them up.
It says here, he would give life back to girls about to be killed at birth,
telling a man wishing to kill his daughter.
Don't kill her.
Give her to me to look after.
When she grows up, you can take her back or if you wish, Give her to me.
So, he would raise up these daughters,
and then go back to the father and say if you want her back,
here she is otherwise, I would still take care of her.
He used to refuse to eat the meat that was slaughtered in Makkah.
It's mentioned that once a meal was presented to Rasool Allah ﷺ,
some meat,
Rasool Allah ﷺ refused it and he passed it over,
so it was given to Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل),
Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل) said I don't eat from this meat which you slaughter for your gods.
He used to, in fact there's a quotation by him;
He would go to the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ),
and he would criticize them for slaughtering their beasts in the names of their gods.
He would say, "sheep were created by God,
and He brings down from the skies, the water that makes vegetation, grow for them from the earth.
So, why do you slaughter them in the name of God other than Allah,
denying all that and venerating them.
He said, Allah is the One, Who created these cattle and you know that
and Allah is the One, Who's bringing down rain for them,
and then you are slaughtering them in the name of other gods.
Now Zaid Bin Amr Bin Nufail(زيد بن عمرو بن نفيل), he died prior to the Prophet hood of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
His son Saeed(سعيد) was one of the believers
and he is one of the 10 who are given the glad tidings of Jannah(جنة), Saeed Bin Zaid(سعيد بن زيد).
Saeed Bin Zaid(سعيد بن زيد) went to Rasool Allah ﷺ and inquired about his father,
he wanted to know what will be the fate of his father?
Because he died before Prophet Hood.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told Saeed(سعيد) that your father will come on the day of judgment as a nation alone.
Rasool Allah ﷺ has given Zaid Bin Amr(زيد بن عمرو) glad tidings of Jannah(جنة).
And he also mentioned that on the Day of Judgment, Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل) will be standing as a nation by himself.
On the day of judgment people are going to be divided into nations
and every nation is led by a Prophet.
So, you'd have the nation of Noah(نوح),
the nation of Musa(موسى),  the nation of Eesa(عيسى), the nation of Ibrahim عليه السّلام.
And you would have the nation of Muhammadﷺ
because Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل), was not part of a particular nation of a Prophet,
he would come on the day of judgment as his own nation,
he would be standing alone.
And that is also an honor for Zaid Bin Nufail(زيد بن نفيل), that he is standing on the Day of Judgment alone
And Allah سبحانه وتعالى will grant him Jannah(جنة),
because he knew the truth and he worshiped Allahسبحانه وتعالى the best he could.
Another example is Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل).
Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) was the cousin of Khadijah رضي الله عنها.
Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل), was a Christian.
And he was a lettered man
and he used to copy some of the Scripture of the Christians and study from it
and he had some of these scrolls.
And he was a believer in one God, he was a believer in Allahعَزّوجَلّ
and again, there were some Christians here and there
who still believed in the oneness of Allah سبحانه وتعالى
and they would not attribute divinity to Eesa عليه السّلام.
Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) was one of them.
And Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) was the one, Khadijah(خديجه) consulted,
When Rasool Allah ﷺ first received the revelation.
Immediately after that, Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) passed away.
So, people were wondering what would happen to Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل).
And some of them were saying Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) is in Hellfire
because he died before Rasool Allah ﷺ started preaching the message,
even though Rasool Allah had received the message, but he didn't start preaching it yet.
And Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) died before that.
So, they said that he would be in Hellfire.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said I have seen him in a dream and he was wearing white clothes,
if he was a man in Hellfire, he wouldn't be wearing white clothes.
Later on, Rasool Allah ﷺ saw another dream
and Rasool Allah ﷺ saw that Waraqah Bin Nofal(ورقه بن نوفل) had two gardens in paradise.
So, he was in Jannah(جنة) because he had the true belief, he had the right belief.
Now the next example is a long one,
it is the story of Salman Al-Farisi رضي الله عنه.
Ibn Abbas رضي الله عنه, he went to Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) when he was old, in his old age
and he requested Salman(سلمان) to tell him his story.
So, Salman(سلمان) is now narrating his story to Ibn Abbas رضي الله عنه.
He says: I was a Persian man from Asfahan(اسفهان).
Asfahan(اسفهان) is in current day Iran from a village called Gee(جي).
And my father was the head man of the town or the village
and I was striving and taking pain in the religion of Al-Majoosiah(ألمجوسيه).
Al-Majoosiah(ألمجوسيه), I think it's translated as Maggian
it's a religion that they believe in good and evil and they worship fire.
So, they believe that there are two forces that are fighting good and evil.
It's a form of Shirk(شرك),
They are considered to be Wasnia(وثنيه), it's not part of Ahlul Kitaab(أهل الكتاب).
So, Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) says; I took pains to be a good Maggian.
And he grew in the religion, until he became the keeper of the fire.
He was the one who would light the fire and the never let it go off.
So, they had this fire in every village they would have in the temple of fire,
and the fire needs to be kept by a certain person to ensure that it's always burning.
And that was supposed to be a high position in their religion, to be the keeper of the fire, the one who was entrusted with the fire.
He said, my father owned a large farm,
one day he was busy constructing a building of his,
and he wanted me to go out and take care of business in the farm.
But Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) says that my father loved me so much,
he closeted me in his house and would never let me leave.
So, Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) says on that particular day, my father was busy with this building of his
and he wanted me to go and take care of some business in his farm.
But then he told me, O my son, you know how dear you are to me,
if you are late, then I would be so concerned about you and
you are more important to me than the farm or my building, so please come early,
Salman Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) literally said,
I was kept in his house, like a slave girl, he would not allow me to go anywhere.
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) he left on that day to go and do this business for his father.
He said, I passed by a church for Christians, it was a Christian church.
And I heard them praying,
So, I wanted to go in and investigate and Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) says;
I didn't know much about people because I never left home.
He said: So this was something new to me.
And I came to realize that there's another religion and some people are praying in a different fashion.
So, I decided to go in, and investigate.
He said: I went into the church.
And I was quite impressed by their method of prayer,
I ended up staying with them until sunset.
And I neglected my father's work.
He said: My father was so worried,
he started sending out people to find me.
I came back late and my father said; O, my son, Didn't I tell you not to be late, what happened?
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) said: I passed next to a church of Christians.
And I went in to see their prayer.
And I forgot to do the job you asked me to.
His father told them all my son, their religion is no good,
and your religion, and the religion of your forefathers is better.
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) responded to his father and said: No
their religion is better than ours.
So, now the father of Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) was extremely worried.
He ended up chaining, his son and imprisoning him at home.
He put chains on his legs.
He was so terrified and afraid that my son, might change his religion,
that he ended up locking him up at home.
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي), when he was at the church, he asked
the church members, where is the center of your religion?
Where did this religion originate from?
So they said from the Holy Land, from Falasteen(فلسطين), from Ash-sham(الشام).
Now, when his father put him in shackles, he managed to send out a message to the church
telling them that if you ever receive or know of a caravan that is in town from Ash-sham(الشام), let me know.
So, a caravan did come in, and they sent him word.
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي), was able to release himself and run away
and he went with this caravan, all the way to the Holy Land in search of the truth.
He arrived in Syria.
And he asked who's the most learned man that you have in this religion.
I mean, he wants to go out and study under the greatest.
He was told go to the bishop in this particular church.
He went to the bishop and he told him, this is my situation, I came all the way, I want to study from you.
So, the bishop told him, you're welcome, you can stay with me.
So, he ended up staying with the bishop in the church living there.
Salman farisi (سلمان فارسی) said: This man used to ask the people, to donate, to give alms, charity
and then he would end up keeping it for himself.
Rather than distributing it to the poor, he would keep it to himself.
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) said: He was such an evil man and I hated him so much.
Nevertheless, I remained with him and then when he died,
the Christians of that church they wanted to have a burial for him and
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) went, and told them this was an evil man.
They said, I mean, how you dare say that?
He said, I'll show you the proof.
And Salman Farsi(سلمان الفارسی) took them to the place where this man used to hide all of the money
and he pulled out seven containers filled with gold and silver.
This man was ripping off the people and keeping the money for himself.
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) said: The people were so angered,
they ended up crucifying his dead body and stoning him,
and then they appointed someone in his place.
Now, Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) says about this particular man.
Then they brought another man to take his place and
I never saw a man, who did not attend the five prayers,
who was better than he, nor more Ascetic, nor more enthusiastic about the afterlife,
nor more devoted both day and night,
I loved him, as I had never loved before.
So now, a truly pious person took his place.
Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) ended up spending time with this man, learning from him,
studying the religion worshiping in the church.
But then death was approaching this man. He was already at old age.
Salman Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) said: I went to him when he was on his deathbed.
And I told him, You know my story.
Now, I came all the way to study this religion.
And now since the decree of Allah is befalling you,
who do you, entrust me to.?
Who would you recommend for me, to continue my study?
He told him, my son I don't know anyone who has done as I have,
people have either died or changed or abandoned most of their prior practices,
except for one man in Mosul(موصل), he practices as I did, so join him.
So now, Salman Al-Farisi(سلمان الفارسي) is going to travel all the way
from Ash-sham, Falastine(فلسطين) or Syria, to Iraq, Al-Mosul(الموصل), in search of knowledge.
The bishop died and Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) embarked on that journey.
And he went to this Bishop of Al-Mosul(الموصل), and he told him, his story.
And he told them that you were recommended to me by the bishop in Ash-sham(الشام).
Would you accept me to be with you? He said: Yes, of course, you can be my student.
So, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) spent time with him.
But this person was also an old man, and he was approaching death.
So, After a short while, he was dying.
So, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) told him,
I came to this person and he recommended you to me and now you're passing away.
Who do you recommend?
He told him, I don't know of anyone who's following the same path of ours, except the Bishop of Nasebeen(نصيبين).
And now, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) is traveling all the way from Mosul(موصل) to Nasebeen(نصيبين),
and he went to the Christian man in Nasebeen(نصيبين) and he told him the story.
I went from this person to this person and now I ended up coming to you.
And he spent time with the Bishop of Nasebeen(نصيبين).
But then this man was approaching death too.
You see, this is a dying breed.
They are dying one after another, and they're leaving no one behind them to carry on the torch.
He went to the scholar in, Nasebeen(نصيبين), he spent time with him.
And he was dying.
And when he was dying; He said I don't know of anyone who's following our way,
except a man in Amooriyah(أموريه), in Byzantine, Turkey.
So now, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) is traveling all the way to Turkey.
Over there in Amooriyah(أموريه), Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي), in addition to his studies
and participation in the worship services, he started a business
and he accumulated enough wealth to purchase some sheep and cow.
When death was approaching his teacher in Amooriyah(أموريه),
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) told him, who do you recommend me to study with?
He responded and said my son, I don't know anyone
who is as we were, to whom to send you to.
But the time is near for a Prophet being sent with Ibrahim(ابراهيم)'s religion, who will come forth in the land of the Arabs,
he will move to refuge to somewhere with date palms growing between two scorched rocky planes,
he has signs that are unmistakable, he eats things given to him as gifts, but not alms
and between his shoulders, there's the seal of Prophet hood.
If you can go there, do so.
So now, the scholar of Amooriyah(أموريه) is saying that there's no one living today, who's following this same path.
The ones, who believe in the true message of Jesus, they have all passed away.
Therefore, it is time for a new message to come.
Because now the world is void of guidance.
So now, it is time to filled that void.
So, a Prophet will come and he's approaching and his time is near,
and he has unmistakable signs, and these are his signs.
Number one, he will take refuge in a place that grows palm trees.
And it is between two rocky tracks, volcanic rock.
He doesn't eat Sadaqah(صدقه), charity, but he accepts gifts.
And there is the seal of Prophet hood a sign between his shoulders on his back.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: I was trying to find a way to reach to the land of the Arabs, it's far away.
He said until, I met some merchants from the tribe of Qalb(قلب).
I ask them to carry me with them,
and I will pay them all of the money that I have, my cows and my sheep, are yours, just take me to the land of the Arabs.
Allah O Akbar(الله اكبر), look at the sacrifice of Salman(سلمان).
I mean, he worked very hard to build up this small business and accumulate this wealth,
and now he's willing to give it up just to be taken, to be transported to the land of the Nabi(نبي).
The story of Salman Al-Farsi(سلمان الفارسي) is an amazing story of someone who searching for Al-Haqeeqah(ألحقيقه), for truth.
They agreed and they carried Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) with them.
When they reached to Arabia to a place called Wadi-El-Qur'ra(وادي القراى).
These merchants ended up betraying Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي),
and they sold him as a slave to a Jewish man.
Now, if you get stuck into slavery that's it, You stuck in there,
and nobody will believe you, if you say that you're a free man.
So, they claimed that he was a slave, and they ended up selling him.
So now, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) was stuck in bondage.
They sold him to this Jewish man.
This Jewish man took him to Wadi-El-Qur'ra(وادي القراى),
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said; When I saw Wadi-El-Qur'ra(وادي القراى), I thought this might be the place that was describe to me,
because, Wadi-El-Qur'ra(وادي القراى) it has some palm trees.
So, he was fine to stay there.
He said, then a cousin of my owner from Banni Quraidha(بني قريظة),
a Jew from Banni Quraidha(بني قريظة), visited my master and he purchased me.
So now, Salman(سلمان) was sold from this man in Wadi-El-Qur'ra(وادي القراى),
and he was sold to a Jew from Bannu Quraidha(بنو قريظة),
where do Bannu Quraidha(بنو قريظة) live?
In Madina.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: I was carried from Wadi-El-Qur'ra(وادي القراى) to Madina
and he said In the name of Allah as soon as I saw Madina, I knew this was the place.
This is it.
Because Madina is very rich with palm groves.
It has a lot of palm trees and it is located between two rocky tracks,
Al-Harrah Al-Sharqiyyah Wal Harrah Al-Gharbiyyah (ألحره ألشرقيه والحره ألغربيه).
These are two rocky tracks of volcanic rocks, scorched very dark.
And by the way, this was the natural protection of Madina.
In the Battle of the trench, did Rasool Allah ﷺ make a trench all over Madina? No..
He dug the trench on one side only,
because on two sides Madina was protected by this rocky track.
These are not mountains, these are very sharp rocks that are filling the plane.
And this is volcanic rock and it's very difficult for an army to move through it.
So, these are two natural barriers and then from the south,
Madina is protected by palm trees, that's where all of the palm groves are.
So, Madina can be attacked from the north, that's the direction where the attack could be made from
and that is where Rasool Allah ﷺ has dug the trench.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: I knew that this was it.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: Rasool Allah ﷺ was sent and he spent years in Makkah.
And I had no idea about it because I was busy in the toils of slavery.
You know, a slave is busy with work and does not have an idea what's going on around him in the world.
So, Salman Al-Farsi(سلمان الفارسي) said: I have no idea that Rasool Allah ﷺ was already preaching the message.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: one day, I was working on top of a palm tree
And my master was sitting under the palm tree.
He said, one of his cousins came to him, and he was angry.
You could see anger on his face and he said: May god damn the children of Qayla(قيله),
children Qayla(قيله) is a name that was given to Al-Aos Wal Khazraj(ألاوس ولخزرج),
the Jews used to call Al-Aos Wal Khazraj(ألاوس ولخزرج), Bannu Qayla(بنو قيله).
He said: May god damn them.
They have assembled in Qubaa(ألقباء), in support of a man, who came from Makkah(مكه) who claims to be a Prophet.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: When I heard that a chill went down my spine
and I started to tremble, and I was almost gonna fall down from the palm tree and land on my master.
Ya'ani(يعني) Subhaan Allah (سبحان الله), Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) has been waiting for this moment for years.
He has given up his life, he has left his family, left his homeland and came into foreign lands
different language, different culture, different people.
I mean, in those days it wasn't easy to travel and go among people, who are foreign.
It's not like today you can have interpreters and translators and access to people, who would speak your language.
In those days it was very difficult.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) had to leave Persia,
and then he went to Ash-Sham(الشام),
and then he went to Turkey and Iraq,
and now he's in the land of the Arabs, which is a very secluded area.
I mean, the land of the Arabs is surrounded by deserts.
It doesn't have contact with the outside world.
The Persians were away from it, the Romans were away from it,
it was a very secluded land, very difficult, very harsh.
And then Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) is living alone as a slave.
You mean, imagine the feelings of homesickness that's such a person would have,
sold as a slave living in a foreign land.
And now he has heard the news, he has been waiting for, for years.
He said: I came running down the tree,
and I went to the man and I was questioning him, I was asking him questions.
He said: My master grabbed me and punched me in my face
and told me; It's none of your business go back to work.
Salman Al-Farsi(سلمان الفارسي) said: Later on, that evening, I prepared some food.
And I traveled to Quba'a(ألقباء) Because Quba'a(ألقباء) outside of Madina,
Quba'a(ألقباء) is in the outskirts of Madina and that's where Rasool Allah ﷺ first arrived,
and he built the Masjid of Quba'a(ألقباء),
now it's pretty much in the district of Madina.
But in those days, it was considered to be an independent village.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: I took some food with me
and I went to visit Rasool Allah ﷺ at night.
He said, I came in and I told Muhammadﷺ, I heard that you are a very good man
and that you have companions who are strangers and needy.
So, I have brought you this food as charity,
and I think that you are the one who deserves it most.
And I handed it to him,
he said: Rasool Allah ﷺ received the food from me,
and then he told his companions to go ahead and eat, but he didn't join in with them.
Sign number one, he does not eat charity.
He does not eat from alms, he does not eat from charity.
He said: I went back and I said now test one is done.
I went back, he said: Later on, I prepared some food,
and I went to the Rasool Allah ﷺ and he was already on his way to Madina.
I said, I went up to him, I greeted him,
and then I told him; Last time I presented you with food and I told you that this is charity and you refuse to eat from it.
So, I want to honor you with this gift,
and he said: I handed the food to Muhammadﷺ,
he said: Muhammadﷺ invited the companions to come in, and eat, and he joined with them,
Sign number two.
He said: And then I went to him and visited him, when he was in Baqiyah Al-Gharqad(بقيه ألغرقد), cemetery of Madina.
He was following a Janazah(جنازه).
He said: I went up to Muhammadﷺ I greeted him and then I went around him, to see the sign on his back.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: Rasool Allah ﷺ sensed
that I was trying to look for something that was described for me.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ uncovered his back he threw off the cloak that was covering his shoulders.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said, and right there in front of my eyes was the seal of Prophet hood,
Sign number three.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said when I saw the seal of Prophet hood on his back.
I fell down and I prostrated myself to Muhammadﷺ, I made Sujood(سجود) to him, and I started kissing his feet and I was crying.
And that was the moment that Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي), has been waiting all of his life for.
So, he made Sujood(سجود) to Muhammadﷺ and he was kissing his feet and weeping, crying.
He said: Rasool Allah ﷺ immediately told me to stand up.
Rasool Allah ﷺ does not accept Sujood(سجود) for him.
So, he told Salman(سلمان) to stand up.
And then he told me, tell me your story.
So, I narrated my story to him.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told me I want you to narrate, this same story to my companions.
I want you to tell them this story,
a story of a man, who was searching for truth, all of his life.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: and I narrated my story to them, just like I am narrating it to you, Ibn Abbas(إبن عباس),
I was mentioning to them, the same thing.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: Because I was a slave,
I ended up missing the Battle of Badr(بدر) and the Battle of Uhud(أحد)
And then Rasool Allah ﷺ told me one day, O Salman(سلمان) free yourself from slavery, Kaatib(كاتب).
Mukatiba(مكاتبه) was a deal that was made by the slave and the master,
that the slave would work for a certain time
and generate a certain income and ransom themselves.
So, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) went to his owner and said: I want to be free.
So, his owner told him, you have to plant for me 300 palm trees and they all have to survive.
So, at the end, I have to have 300 living palm trees
and you pay me 40 ounces of gold.
So, he came to Rasool Allah ﷺ said: this is the huge amount of money that I have to pay to ransom myself.
Rasool Allah ﷺ said, don't worry.
And then Rasool Ullah gathered the Sahabah and told them, help your brother!
So, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: Some of them would bring 30 seedlings of a palm tree,
some of them would bring 20, some 15, everyone would bring as much as they can,
until I had 300 seedlings.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told him, when you collect the 300 seedlings
go and dig the holes for them, but do not plant them, come and tell me first.
So, Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) gathered the 300 seedlings, he went and he dug the holes for them.
And then he went to Rasool Allah ﷺ and said it's already.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said,
Rasool Allah ﷺ by himself would go and carry the seedlings and plant them one by one with his own blessed hands.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said, None of those 300 palm trees died, they all grew, they all survived.
Now the ratio of palm trees that end up growing is usually you have a small ratio many of them die, at that young age
because of their fragility and the heat of the desert and the difficult weather.
But Rasool Allah ﷺ wanted to do it himself so that they would survive.
So, he planted them one by one and they all lived.
So, now Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) had to pay 40 ounces of gold
and he had no clue where he's going to get that amount of money from.
Later on one day, a small amount of gold was given to Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, the Messenger of Allah said: Where is the Persian man, where's your Persian brother?
أين اَخَو كُمُ الْفَارِسِيْ
So, they went and called Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي),
Rasool Allah ﷺ told them take this gold and free yourself, with it.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: O Rasool Allah, what would this do?
When Salman(سلمان) saw the amount of gold, it appeared to be very small and wouldn't be sufficient.
Rasool Allah ﷺ told them take it and it will be enough.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) said: I took it and it was weighed and it came out 40 ounces exactly.
He said and then I was free and I never missed anything with Rasool Allah ﷺ after that,
and the first battle he participated in, was.?
Al-Khandaq(الخندق).
And we all know his participation in it.
He was the one, who came up with the idea of the trench.
So, that is the story of Salman Al-Farsi رضي الله عنه
A few notes on his story,
Who is the first man Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) ended up studying with?
He was the bishop in Syria,
What does Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) say about him?
He said: So I joined him, but he was an evil man, demanding alms from his people,
and whatever they collected, he would store away for himself and not give to the poor.
Eventually, he had gathered seven jars of gold and silver,
I hated him mightily for what I saw him doing.
So, here we have somebody who's in search of the truth
and he ends up meeting a person who has all the qualifications of turning him away of making him give up.
But the zeal that Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) had was stronger than that.
Nowadays, we say that sometimes our actions as Muslims is what causes the people to turn away from Islam.
Well, that is true to a certain extent.
But if somebody is sincere in their search of finding the truth,
they should realize and understand that the truth is something and what the people are doing is something else.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) did not reject Christianity because the man he met was such a corrupt person.
He stuck with him and he remained
and then Allah سبحانه وتعالى rewarded him for that later on.
He ended up being with the best man that he has ever seen.
And in the description of that man, what did he say?
He said, then they brought another man to take his place
and I never saw a man, who did not attend the five prayers, who was better than he,
What Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) means by a man who did not attend the five daily prayers is, that
this is the best man I have ever seen before meeting the Muslims, before the followers of Muhammadﷺ
because they are the ones who pray five times a day.
So, he said the best person I met the most righteous and pious person I met
before I met the Sahabah(صحابہ) of Rasool Allah ﷺ was this man,
Allah rewarded him for his Sabr(صبر) and patience.
And we learned two things from this.
Number one
Allah سبحانه وتعالى says:
وَالَّذِينَ اهْتَدَوْا زَادَهُمْ هُدًى وَآتَاهُمْ تَقْوَاهُمْ۝
The ones, who search for guidance, Allah will give it to them, but you have to look for it,
you have to put in some effort.
And when you do the reward that you get is more than what you put in.
If you walk towards Allah, Allah will run towards you.
If you take one step towards Allah, Allah will take many steps towards you
but you have to take that first step, you have to take it.
Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي) was searching for it and he got it.
Allah سبحانه وتعالى ended up guiding him even though he belonged to a land that was hundreds of miles away,
but he ended up receiving the truth because of his sincerity.
Number two, we shouldn't be turned off or let down, when we see somebody who's not doing the right thing.
That is something that has nothing to do with the message itself.
And Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي), he realized that and he remained with the man until he died and then he ended up being with a better person.
The second note is that there were remnants of true believers before the time of Rasool Allah ﷺ,
but they were dying, and they were not leaving anyone behind them.
And that is why the world was thirsty for the message of Muhammadﷺ.
The third lesson to learn is that the Muslim community must be supportive of its new members.
Rasool Allah ﷺ helped Salman Farsi(سلمان فارسي), free himself, from slavery.
And he requested the Sahabah to pitch in and participate
as Muslims living in the West, it will become a duty among us,
to take care of the needs of the new comers to the religion
And many times these needs will be financial.
And they need to be helped
and this is part of Da'wah(دعوة)
because Da'wah(دعوة) is not that you throw out words which are free to give, it doesn't cost you anything.
Da'wah(دعوة) is also that you have to be responsible for the people who will join in your ranks.
And notice that many of the early Muslims were people who were in need Bilal رضي الله عنه was freed by Abu Bakr(ابو بكر).
Many of the early Muslims were slaves that were in need of a lot of financial help
because they were thrown away by their masters.
Or you would have for example someone like Mus'ab Ibn Umair(مصعب ابن عمير), who came from a very wealthy family
but his mother refused to give him anything after he became Muslim.
So, these members are in need of support in their initial stages.
And the risk is that if they don't get help in those critical stages, they could apostate,
and there is a study that was done in America that found that quite a significant number of reverts end up leaving Islam.
Quite a large number, I don't remember the exact figure,
but a lot of them end up leaving Islam because of the difficulties that they face.
First of all many of them are stripped, from their social belonging,
their social life, their families neglect them, their friends leave them,
so they are in need of a social belonging they have to have a new Association.
Number two, many of them come with some dire financial needs
and if they don't get them you know a human being is a human being,
if the belly is going empty,
like I mentioned in the Hadith(حديث),
بَازِرُوْ بِالْاَعْمَالِ سَبْعَه هَلْ تَنْتَظِرُوْنَ اِلَّا فَقْرًا مُنْسِيْهَ
Rasool Allah ﷺ said: Do the good deeds before seven things could happen.
And one of them is Faqram Munsiyyah(فَقْرًا مُنْسِيْه) poverty that will make you forget,
if your stomach is empty, you will forget everything.
A person who is going around hungry,
cannot think about spirituality and learning Ilm(علم) and knowledge,
a person in that stage would want to feed their stomach.
So, these are things that are part of our program of Da'wah(دعوة), we have to have institutions
that would satisfy and fulfill the needs of the new Muslim.
And that is part of our duty as Muslims living in non Muslim societies,
where there are people who are embracing Islam.
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرًا